[
  {
    "question": "I want to understand it.",
    "answer": "Quiero comprenderlo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprenderlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprenderlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to understand you.",
    "answer": "Quiero comprenderte.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprenderte."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprenderte."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you understand me?",
    "answer": "¿Puedes comprenderme?",
    "options": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "comprenderme?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "comprenderme?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why can't you understand me?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no puedes comprenderme?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "puedes",
      "comprenderme?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "puedes",
      "comprenderme?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can't understand you.",
    "answer": "No puedo comprenderte.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "comprenderte."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "comprenderte."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can't tell you now",
    "answer": "No puedo decirte ahora.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "decirte",
      "ahora."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "decirte",
      "ahora."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you want to tell me?",
    "answer": "¿Por que no quieres decirme?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "que",
      "no",
      "quieres",
      "decirme?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "que",
      "no",
      "quieres",
      "decirme?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is Pedro.",
    "answer": "Es Pedro.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "Pedro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "Pedro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is he Pedro or Miguel?",
    "answer": "¿Es Pedro o Miguel?",
    "options": [
      "¿Es",
      "Pedro",
      "o",
      "Miguel?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Es",
      "Pedro",
      "o",
      "Miguel?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Pedro American or Spanish?",
    "answer": "¿Pedro es americano o español?",
    "options": [
      "¿Pedro",
      "es",
      "americano",
      "o",
      "español?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Pedro",
      "es",
      "americano",
      "o",
      "español?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am Paula and I’m Spanish.",
    "answer": "Soy Paula y soy española.",
    "options": [
      "Soy",
      "Paula",
      "y",
      "soy",
      "española."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Soy",
      "Paula",
      "y",
      "soy",
      "española."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "if",
    "answer": "si",
    "options": [
      "si"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "si"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't know if you can see me.",
    "answer": "No sé si puedes verme.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "puedes",
      "verme."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "puedes",
      "verme."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't know if he is Spanish or British.",
    "answer": "No sé si es español o británico.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "es",
      "español",
      "o",
      "británico."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "es",
      "español",
      "o",
      "británico."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I understand",
    "answer": "comprendo",
    "options": [
      "comprendo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "comprendo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you understand",
    "answer": "comprendes",
    "options": [
      "comprendes"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "comprendes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "he/she understands",
    "answer": "El/ella comprende",
    "options": [
      "El/ella",
      "comprende"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "El/ella",
      "comprende"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to know if you understand.",
    "answer": "(Ella) quiere saber si comprendes.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "saber",
      "si",
      "comprendes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "saber",
      "si",
      "comprendes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to know if he understands.",
    "answer": "Quiere saber si comprende.",
    "options": [
      "Quiere",
      "saber",
      "si",
      "comprende."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiere",
      "saber",
      "si",
      "comprende."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to say/tell",
    "answer": "decir",
    "options": [
      "decir"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "decir"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She doesn’t want to tell me if she’s leaving tonight.",
    "answer": "No quiere decirme si sale esta noche.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "quiere",
      "decirme",
      "si",
      "sale",
      "esta",
      "noche."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "quiere",
      "decirme",
      "si",
      "sale",
      "esta",
      "noche."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If I don’t see you today, you can tell me tomorrow.",
    "answer": "Si no te veo hoy, puedes decirme mañana.",
    "options": [
      "Si",
      "no",
      "te",
      "veo",
      "hoy,",
      "puedes",
      "decirme",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Si",
      "no",
      "te",
      "veo",
      "hoy,",
      "puedes",
      "decirme",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Don't you see where I am?",
    "answer": "¿No ves dónde estoy?",
    "options": [
      "¿No",
      "ves",
      "dónde",
      "estoy?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿No",
      "ves",
      "dónde",
      "estoy?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can see you .",
    "answer": "Puedo verte.",
    "options": [
      "Puedo",
      "verte."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedo",
      "verte."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I see you.",
    "answer": "Te veo.",
    "options": [
      "Te",
      "veo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Te",
      "veo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You can see me.",
    "answer": "Puedes verme.",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "verme."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "verme."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You see me.",
    "answer": "Me ves.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "ves."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "ves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can understand you.",
    "answer": "Puedo comprenderte.",
    "options": [
      "Puedo",
      "comprenderte."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedo",
      "comprenderte."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I understand you.",
    "answer": "Te comprendo.",
    "options": [
      "Te",
      "comprendo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Te",
      "comprendo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I know",
    "answer": "(yo) sé",
    "options": [
      "(yo)",
      "sé"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(yo)",
      "sé"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to know.",
    "answer": "Quiero saber.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "saber."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "saber."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to know it.",
    "answer": "Quiero saberlo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "saberlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "saberlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I know it.",
    "answer": "Lo sé.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "sé."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "sé."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You know it.",
    "answer": "Lo sabes.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "sabes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "sabes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you know it?",
    "answer": "¿Lo sabes?",
    "options": [
      "¿Lo",
      "sabes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Lo",
      "sabes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you know it?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no lo sabes?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "sabes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "sabes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She knows it.",
    "answer": "(Ella) lo sabe.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "lo",
      "sabe."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "lo",
      "sabe."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to know it.",
    "answer": "(Ella) quiere saberlo.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "saberlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "saberlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I have it.",
    "answer": "Lo tengo.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "tengo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "tengo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to have it.",
    "answer": "Quiero tenerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "tenerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "tenerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you want to have it?",
    "answer": "¿Quieres tenerlo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "tenerlo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "tenerlo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does he want to have it?",
    "answer": "¿Por que quiere tenerlo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "que",
      "quiere",
      "tenerlo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "que",
      "quiere",
      "tenerlo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does he want to do it?",
    "answer": "¿Donde quiere hacerlo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Donde",
      "quiere",
      "hacerlo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Donde",
      "quiere",
      "hacerlo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I do it.",
    "answer": "Lo hago.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "hago."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "hago."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am doing it.",
    "answer": "Lo hago.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "hago."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "hago."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are doing it.",
    "answer": "Lo haces.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "haces."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "haces."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You know (how) to do it.",
    "answer": "Sabes hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Sabes",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Sabes",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I know how to do it for you.",
    "answer": "Sé hacerlo para ti.",
    "options": [
      "Sé",
      "hacerlo",
      "para",
      "ti."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Sé",
      "hacerlo",
      "para",
      "ti."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to eat it.",
    "answer": "Quiero comerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "comerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "comerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am eating it.",
    "answer": "Lo como.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "como."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "como."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you tell me if I can have it today?",
    "answer": "Puedes decirme si puedo tenerlo hoy?",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "decirme",
      "si",
      "puedo",
      "tenerlo",
      "hoy?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "decirme",
      "si",
      "puedo",
      "tenerlo",
      "hoy?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She can tell you if it’s important.",
    "answer": "(Ella) puede decirte si es importante.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "puede",
      "decirte",
      "si",
      "es",
      "importante."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "puede",
      "decirte",
      "si",
      "es",
      "importante."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm sure I can do it if it’s easy.",
    "answer": "Estoy seguro que puedo hacerlo si es fácil.",
    "options": [
      "Estoy",
      "seguro",
      "que",
      "puedo",
      "hacerlo",
      "si",
      "es",
      "fácil."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Estoy",
      "seguro",
      "que",
      "puedo",
      "hacerlo",
      "si",
      "es",
      "fácil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don’t know If you want to tell me.",
    "answer": "No sé si quieres decirme.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "quieres",
      "decirme."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "quieres",
      "decirme."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to buy",
    "answer": "comprar",
    "options": [
      "comprar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "comprar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm sorry but I can’t buy it for you.",
    "answer": "Lo siento pero no puedo comprarlo para ti.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "siento",
      "pero",
      "no",
      "puedo",
      "comprarlo",
      "para",
      "ti."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "siento",
      "pero",
      "no",
      "puedo",
      "comprarlo",
      "para",
      "ti."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you buy it for me?",
    "answer": "Puedes comprarlo para mi?",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "comprarlo",
      "para",
      "mi?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "comprarlo",
      "para",
      "mi?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you want to buy here?",
    "answer": "¿Que quieres comprar aqui?",
    "options": [
      "¿Que",
      "quieres",
      "comprar",
      "aqui?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Que",
      "quieres",
      "comprar",
      "aqui?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you want to buy it?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no quieres comprarlo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "quieres",
      "comprarlo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "quieres",
      "comprarlo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "expensive",
    "answer": "caro",
    "options": [
      "caro"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "caro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's very expensive.",
    "answer": "Es muy caro.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can buy it because it’s not very expensive.",
    "answer": "Puedo comprarlo porque no es muy caro.",
    "options": [
      "Puedo",
      "comprarlo",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedo",
      "comprarlo",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She doesn't want to buy it if it’s not good.",
    "answer": "No quiere comprarlo si no es bueno.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "quiere",
      "comprarlo",
      "si",
      "no",
      "es",
      "bueno."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "quiere",
      "comprarlo",
      "si",
      "no",
      "es",
      "bueno."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not buying it because it’s expensive and it’s very bad.",
    "answer": "No lo compro porque es caro y es muy malo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "compro",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "caro",
      "y",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "malo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "compro",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "caro",
      "y",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "malo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "new",
    "answer": "nuevo",
    "options": [
      "nuevo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "nuevo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to buy a new car.",
    "answer": "Quiero comprar un carro nuevo",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprar",
      "un",
      "carro",
      "nuevo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprar",
      "un",
      "carro",
      "nuevo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to buy a new house.",
    "answer": "(Ella) quiere comprar una casa nueva.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "comprar",
      "una",
      "casa",
      "nueva."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "comprar",
      "una",
      "casa",
      "nueva."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to buy it because it’s not very expensive and she needs it today.",
    "answer": "Quiere comprarlo porque no es muy caro/a y lo necesita hoy.",
    "options": [
      "Quiere",
      "comprarlo",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro/a",
      "y",
      "lo",
      "necesita",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiere",
      "comprarlo",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro/a",
      "y",
      "lo",
      "necesita",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The house  is very expensive.",
    "answer": "La casa es muy cara.",
    "options": [
      "La",
      "casa",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "cara."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "La",
      "casa",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "cara."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "how much",
    "answer": "¿cuánto?",
    "options": [
      "¿cuánto?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿cuánto?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How much is it?",
    "answer": "¿Cuánto es?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cuánto",
      "es?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cuánto",
      "es?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to know how much it is.",
    "answer": "Quiero saber cuánto es.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "saber",
      "cuánto",
      "es."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "saber",
      "cuánto",
      "es."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to buy it but she doesn’t know how much it is.",
    "answer": "(Ella) quiere comprarlo pero no sabe cuánto es.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "comprarlo",
      "pero",
      "no",
      "sabe",
      "cuánto",
      "es."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "comprarlo",
      "pero",
      "no",
      "sabe",
      "cuánto",
      "es."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you sure you know how much it is?",
    "answer": "¿Estas seguro/a que sabes cuánto es?",
    "options": [
      "¿Estas",
      "seguro/a",
      "que",
      "sabes",
      "cuánto",
      "es?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Estas",
      "seguro/a",
      "que",
      "sabes",
      "cuánto",
      "es?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where do you want to buy it?",
    "answer": "¿Dónde quieres comprarlo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Dónde",
      "quieres",
      "comprarlo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Dónde",
      "quieres",
      "comprarlo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you buy it here, it’s not very expensive.",
    "answer": "Si lo compras aquí, no es muy caro/a.",
    "options": [
      "Si",
      "lo",
      "compras",
      "aquí,",
      "no",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro/a."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Si",
      "lo",
      "compras",
      "aquí,",
      "no",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro/a."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you tell me how much it is today?",
    "answer": "¿Puedes decirme cuánto es hoy?",
    "options": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "decirme",
      "cuánto",
      "es",
      "hoy?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "decirme",
      "cuánto",
      "es",
      "hoy?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to buy it if it’s not expensive.",
    "answer": "Quiero comprarlo si no es caro/a.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprarlo",
      "si",
      "no",
      "es",
      "caro/a."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprarlo",
      "si",
      "no",
      "es",
      "caro/a."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am going",
    "answer": "voy a",
    "options": [
      "voy",
      "a"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "voy",
      "a"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am going to do it.",
    "answer": "Voy a hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am going to buy it.",
    "answer": "Voy a comprarlo.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "comprarlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "comprarlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am going to eat now.",
    "answer": "Voy a comer ahora.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "comer",
      "ahora."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "comer",
      "ahora."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "late",
    "answer": "tarde",
    "options": [
      "tarde"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "tarde"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's very late.",
    "answer": "Es muy tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "muy",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "muy",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "more",
    "answer": "más",
    "options": [
      "más"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "más"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "later (more late)",
    "answer": "más tarde",
    "options": [
      "más",
      "tarde"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "más",
      "tarde"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to be here later.",
    "answer": "Voy a estar aquí más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "aquí",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "aquí",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I have to do it now because it’s very late.",
    "answer": "Tengo que hacerlo ahora porque es muy tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Tengo",
      "que",
      "hacerlo",
      "ahora",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Tengo",
      "que",
      "hacerlo",
      "ahora",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to do it later.",
    "answer": "Voy a hacerlo más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not going to",
    "answer": "no voy a",
    "options": [
      "no",
      "voy",
      "a"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "no",
      "voy",
      "a"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not going to do it now because I’m going to be busy today.",
    "answer": "No voy a hacerlo ahora, porque voy a estar ocupado/a hoy.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "ahora,",
      "porque",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "ocupado/a",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "ahora,",
      "porque",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "ocupado/a",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not going to buy it because it’s very expensive.",
    "answer": "No voy a comprarlo porque es muy caro.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "comprarlo",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "comprarlo",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to tell you later.",
    "answer": "Voy a decirte más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "decirte",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "decirte",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm doing it now because I’m not going to do it later.",
    "answer": "Lo hago ahora porque no voy a hacerlo más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "hago",
      "ahora",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "hago",
      "ahora",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to call",
    "answer": "llamar",
    "options": [
      "llamar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "llamar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to call you later.",
    "answer": "Voy a llamarte más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "llamarte",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "llamarte",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can't call you later because I don’t have my telephone.",
    "answer": "No puedo llamarte más tarde porque no tengo mi teléfono.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "llamarte",
      "más",
      "tarde",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "tengo",
      "mi",
      "teléfono."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "llamarte",
      "más",
      "tarde",
      "porque",
      "no",
      "tengo",
      "mi",
      "teléfono."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You can call me if you have your telephone.",
    "answer": "Puedes llamarme si tienes tu teléfono.",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "llamarme",
      "si",
      "tienes",
      "tu",
      "teléfono."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "llamarme",
      "si",
      "tienes",
      "tu",
      "teléfono."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "at what time?",
    "answer": "¿a qué hora?",
    "options": [
      "¿a",
      "qué",
      "hora?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿a",
      "qué",
      "hora?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time can you call me?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora puedes llamarme?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "puedes",
      "llamarme?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "puedes",
      "llamarme?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If she has the computer, she can call you.",
    "answer": "Si tiene el ordenador, puede llamarte.",
    "options": [
      "Si",
      "tiene",
      "el",
      "ordenador,",
      "puede",
      "llamarte."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Si",
      "tiene",
      "el",
      "ordenador,",
      "puede",
      "llamarte."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to be there later.",
    "answer": "Voy a estar allí más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "allí",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "allí",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not going to be here tomorrow.",
    "answer": "No voy a estar aquí mañana.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "aquí",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "aquí",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to put",
    "answer": "poner",
    "options": [
      "poner"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "poner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to put it on the table.",
    "answer": "Voy a ponerlo en la mesa.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "ponerlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "ponerlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not going to put it on the chair.",
    "answer": "No voy a ponerlo en la silla.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "ponerlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "silla."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "ponerlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "silla."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "are you going to? /you are going to",
    "answer": "¿vas a?  /vas a ...",
    "options": [
      "¿vas",
      "a?",
      "",
      "/vas",
      "a",
      "..."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿vas",
      "a?",
      "",
      "/vas",
      "a",
      "..."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going to call me?",
    "answer": "¿Vas a llamarme?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "llamarme?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "llamarme?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time are you going to call me?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora vas a llamarme?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "llamarme?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "llamarme?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time are you going to be here tonight?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora vas a estar aquí esta noche?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "aquí",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "aquí",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are you going to be later?",
    "answer": "¿Dónde vas a estar más tarde?",
    "options": [
      "¿Dónde",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "más",
      "tarde?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Dónde",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "más",
      "tarde?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why aren’t you going to do it for me?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no vas a hacerlo para mi?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "para",
      "mi?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "para",
      "mi?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "she/he/it is going to",
    "answer": "va a",
    "options": [
      "va",
      "a"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "va",
      "a"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She is going to do it.",
    "answer": "(Ella) va a hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He’s going to call me later.",
    "answer": "Va a llamarme más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "llamarme",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "llamarme",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's going to put it in the house.",
    "answer": "Va a ponerlo en la casa.",
    "options": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "ponerlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "casa."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "ponerlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "casa."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He's going to need a hotel for tonight.",
    "answer": "Va a necesitar un hotel para esta noche.",
    "options": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "necesitar",
      "un",
      "hotel",
      "para",
      "esta",
      "noche."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "necesitar",
      "un",
      "hotel",
      "para",
      "esta",
      "noche."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not going to do it like that.",
    "answer": "No voy a hacerlo así.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "así."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "así."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I see that you're not going to tell me.",
    "answer": "Veo que no vas a decirme.",
    "options": [
      "Veo",
      "que",
      "no",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "decirme."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Veo",
      "que",
      "no",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "decirme."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you understand that she’s not going to do it?",
    "answer": "¿Comprendes que no va a hacerlo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Comprendes",
      "que",
      "no",
      "va",
      "a",
      "hacerlo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Comprendes",
      "que",
      "no",
      "va",
      "a",
      "hacerlo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "ready",
    "answer": "listo/a",
    "options": [
      "listo/a"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "listo/a"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am ready (female speaker)",
    "answer": "Estoy lista.",
    "options": [
      "Estoy",
      "lista."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Estoy",
      "lista."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am ready (male speaker)",
    "answer": "Estoy listo.",
    "options": [
      "Estoy",
      "listo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Estoy",
      "listo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you ready?",
    "answer": "¿Estás listo/a?",
    "options": [
      "¿Estás",
      "listo/a?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Estás",
      "listo/a?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time are you going to be ready?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora vas a estar listo/a?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo/a?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo/a?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time is it going to be ready?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora va a estar listo?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "soon",
    "answer": "pronto",
    "options": [
      "pronto"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "pronto"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's going to be ready soon.",
    "answer": "Va a estar listo pronto.",
    "options": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "See you soon!",
    "answer": "¡Hasta pronto!",
    "options": [
      "¡Hasta",
      "pronto!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Hasta",
      "pronto!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going see it soon?",
    "answer": "¿Vas a verlo pronto?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "pronto?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "pronto?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's not going to be ready because she’s very busy.",
    "answer": "No va a estar lista porque está muy ocupada.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "lista",
      "porque",
      "está",
      "muy",
      "ocupada."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "lista",
      "porque",
      "está",
      "muy",
      "ocupada."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time are you going to have dinner?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora vas a cenar?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "cenar?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vas",
      "a",
      "cenar?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to have dinner soon.",
    "answer": "Voy a cenar pronto.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "cenar",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "cenar",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are you leaving now?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué sales ahora?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "sales",
      "ahora?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "sales",
      "ahora?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm leaving now because I have to be there soon.",
    "answer": "Salgo ahora porque tengo que estar allí pronto.",
    "options": [
      "Salgo",
      "ahora",
      "porque",
      "tengo",
      "que",
      "estar",
      "allí",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Salgo",
      "ahora",
      "porque",
      "tengo",
      "que",
      "estar",
      "allí",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "everything/all",
    "answer": "todo",
    "options": [
      "todo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "todo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Everything is going to be ready for you today.",
    "answer": "Todo va a estar listo para tí hoy.",
    "options": [
      "Todo",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "para",
      "tí",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Todo",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "para",
      "tí",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's impossible to do it all today.",
    "answer": "Es imposible hacerlo todo hoy.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "imposible",
      "hacerlo",
      "todo",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "imposible",
      "hacerlo",
      "todo",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you have everything?",
    "answer": "¿Tienes todo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Tienes",
      "todo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Tienes",
      "todo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Does she have everything ready for me?",
    "answer": "¿Tiene todo listo para mi?",
    "options": [
      "¿Tiene",
      "todo",
      "listo",
      "para",
      "mi?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Tiene",
      "todo",
      "listo",
      "para",
      "mi?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going to eat all that?",
    "answer": "¿Vas a comer todo eso?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "comer",
      "todo",
      "eso?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "comer",
      "todo",
      "eso?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going to do all this?",
    "answer": "¿Vas a hacer todo esto?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "hacer",
      "todo",
      "esto?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "hacer",
      "todo",
      "esto?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is everything ready now?",
    "answer": "¿Esta todo listo ahora?",
    "options": [
      "¿Esta",
      "todo",
      "listo",
      "ahora?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Esta",
      "todo",
      "listo",
      "ahora?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's leaving soon.",
    "answer": "(Ella) sale pronto.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "sale",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "sale",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "nothing",
    "answer": "nada",
    "options": [
      "nada"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "nada"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nothing is going to be ready today.",
    "answer": "Nada va a estar listo hoy.",
    "options": [
      "Nada",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Nada",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Everything is going to be ready tomorrow.",
    "answer": "Todo va a estar listo mañana.",
    "options": [
      "Todo",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Todo",
      "va",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nothing is in the house because everything is in the car.",
    "answer": "Nada está en la casa porque todo está en el carro.",
    "options": [
      "Nada",
      "está",
      "en",
      "la",
      "casa",
      "porque",
      "todo",
      "está",
      "en",
      "el",
      "carro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Nada",
      "está",
      "en",
      "la",
      "casa",
      "porque",
      "todo",
      "está",
      "en",
      "el",
      "carro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to be ready.",
    "answer": "Quiero estar listo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "estar",
      "listo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "estar",
      "listo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am ready.",
    "answer": "Estoy listo/a.",
    "options": [
      "Estoy",
      "listo/a."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Estoy",
      "listo/a."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are ready.",
    "answer": "Estás listo/a.",
    "options": [
      "Estás",
      "listo/a."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Estás",
      "listo/a."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is ready.",
    "answer": "(Él) está listo.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "está",
      "listo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "está",
      "listo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She is ready.",
    "answer": "(Ella) está lista.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "está",
      "lista."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "está",
      "lista."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nothing is ready.",
    "answer": "Nada está listo.",
    "options": [
      "Nada",
      "está",
      "listo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Nada",
      "está",
      "listo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Everything is ready.",
    "answer": "Todo está listo.",
    "options": [
      "Todo",
      "está",
      "listo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Todo",
      "está",
      "listo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It is ready. (referring to a feminine object)",
    "answer": "Está lista.",
    "options": [
      "Está",
      "lista."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Está",
      "lista."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It’s important.",
    "answer": "Es importante.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "importante."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "importante."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's possible.",
    "answer": "Es posible.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "posible."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "posible."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am",
    "answer": "(yo) soy/estoy",
    "options": [
      "(yo)",
      "soy/estoy"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(yo)",
      "soy/estoy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you are",
    "answer": "(tú) eres/estás",
    "options": [
      "(tú)",
      "eres/estás"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(tú)",
      "eres/estás"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "he is",
    "answer": "(él) es/está",
    "options": [
      "(él)",
      "es/está"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(él)",
      "es/está"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "she is",
    "answer": "(ella) es/está",
    "options": [
      "(ella)",
      "es/está"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(ella)",
      "es/está"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How are you?",
    "answer": "¿Cómo estás?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "estás?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "estás?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is she?",
    "answer": "¿Cómo está (ella)?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(ella)?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(ella)?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is he?",
    "answer": "¿Cómo está (él)?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(él)?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(él)?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "a teacher",
    "answer": "un profesor",
    "options": [
      "un",
      "profesor"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "un",
      "profesor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "a student",
    "answer": "un estudiante",
    "options": [
      "un",
      "estudiante"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "un",
      "estudiante"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm a teacher",
    "answer": "Soy profesor/profesora.",
    "options": [
      "Soy",
      "profesor/profesora."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Soy",
      "profesor/profesora."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm a student",
    "answer": "Soy estudiante.",
    "options": [
      "Soy",
      "estudiante."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Soy",
      "estudiante."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's a student.",
    "answer": "(Ella) es estudiante.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "es",
      "estudiante."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "es",
      "estudiante."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's ready.",
    "answer": "(Ella) está lista.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "está",
      "lista."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "está",
      "lista."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He's a teacher.",
    "answer": "(Él) es profesor.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "es",
      "profesor."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "es",
      "profesor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He's busy.",
    "answer": "Está ocupado.",
    "options": [
      "Está",
      "ocupado."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Está",
      "ocupado."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You’re a student.",
    "answer": "Eres estudiante.",
    "options": [
      "Eres",
      "estudiante."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Eres",
      "estudiante."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You're tired.(referring-to-a-female)",
    "answer": "Estás cansada.",
    "options": [
      "Estás",
      "cansada."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Estás",
      "cansada."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm Peter",
    "answer": "Soy Peter.",
    "options": [
      "Soy",
      "Peter."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Soy",
      "Peter."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm here.",
    "answer": "Estoy aquí.",
    "options": [
      "Estoy",
      "aquí."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Estoy",
      "aquí."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "with",
    "answer": "con",
    "options": [
      "con"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "con"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "with me",
    "answer": "conmigo",
    "options": [
      "conmigo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "conmigo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "with you",
    "answer": "contigo",
    "options": [
      "contigo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "contigo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to do it with you.",
    "answer": "Quiero hacerlo contigo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "hacerlo",
      "contigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "hacerlo",
      "contigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you want to do it with me?",
    "answer": "¿Quieres hacerlo conmigo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "hacerlo",
      "conmigo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "hacerlo",
      "conmigo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't want to do anything (nothing) with you.",
    "answer": "No quiero hacer nada contigo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "hacer",
      "nada",
      "contigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "hacer",
      "nada",
      "contigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to do it with María.",
    "answer": "Quiero hacerlo con María.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "hacerlo",
      "con",
      "María."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "hacerlo",
      "con",
      "María."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you want to have dinner with me?",
    "answer": "¿Quieres cenar conmigo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "cenar",
      "conmigo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "cenar",
      "conmigo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to speak",
    "answer": "hablar",
    "options": [
      "hablar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "hablar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Spanish",
    "answer": "español",
    "options": [
      "español"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "español"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You can speak Spanish with me.",
    "answer": "Puedes hablar español conmigo.",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "hablar",
      "español",
      "conmigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "hablar",
      "español",
      "conmigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "English",
    "answer": "inglés",
    "options": [
      "inglés"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "inglés"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "with him, with her",
    "answer": "con él, con ella",
    "options": [
      "con",
      "él,",
      "con",
      "ella"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "con",
      "él,",
      "con",
      "ella"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You can speak English with him.",
    "answer": "Puedes hablar inglés con él.",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "hablar",
      "inglés",
      "con",
      "él."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "hablar",
      "inglés",
      "con",
      "él."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have to speak Spanish with her.",
    "answer": "Tienes que hablar español con ella.",
    "options": [
      "Tienes",
      "que",
      "hablar",
      "español",
      "con",
      "ella."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Tienes",
      "que",
      "hablar",
      "español",
      "con",
      "ella."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Excuse me! Do you speak english?",
    "answer": "¡Perdone! ¿Hablas inglés?",
    "options": [
      "¡Perdone!",
      "¿Hablas",
      "inglés?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Perdone!",
      "¿Hablas",
      "inglés?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She doesn’t speak English, but she speaks Spanish.",
    "answer": "Ella no habla inglés, pero habla español.",
    "options": [
      "Ella",
      "no",
      "habla",
      "inglés,",
      "pero",
      "habla",
      "español."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Ella",
      "no",
      "habla",
      "inglés,",
      "pero",
      "habla",
      "español."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm not Spanish but I speak Spanish.",
    "answer": "No soy español, pero hablo español.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "soy",
      "español,",
      "pero",
      "hablo",
      "español."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "soy",
      "español,",
      "pero",
      "hablo",
      "español."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I’m not English but I speak English.",
    "answer": "No soy inglés, pero hablo inglés.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "soy",
      "inglés,",
      "pero",
      "hablo",
      "inglés."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "soy",
      "inglés,",
      "pero",
      "hablo",
      "inglés."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to say it in Spanish.",
    "answer": "Voy a decirlo en español.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "decirlo",
      "en",
      "español."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "decirlo",
      "en",
      "español."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to come",
    "answer": "venir",
    "options": [
      "venir"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "venir"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You can come with me.",
    "answer": "Puedes venir conmigo.",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "venir",
      "conmigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "venir",
      "conmigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you come and see it with me tonight?",
    "answer": "¿Puedes venir a verlo conmigo esta noche?",
    "options": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "venir",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "conmigo",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "venir",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "conmigo",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can't come and do it if you are not there.",
    "answer": "No puedo venir a hacerlo si (tú) no estás allí.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "venir",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "si",
      "(tú)",
      "no",
      "estás",
      "allí."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "venir",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "si",
      "(tú)",
      "no",
      "estás",
      "allí."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to go with you.",
    "answer": "Quiero ir contigo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "ir",
      "contigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "ir",
      "contigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I’m not going to go with Carlos.",
    "answer": "No voy a ir con Carlos.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "ir",
      "con",
      "Carlos."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "ir",
      "con",
      "Carlos."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You can go later if you want.",
    "answer": "Puedes ir más tarde si quieres.",
    "options": [
      "Puedes",
      "ir",
      "más",
      "tarde",
      "si",
      "quieres."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Puedes",
      "ir",
      "más",
      "tarde",
      "si",
      "quieres."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to go and and see it with him.",
    "answer": "Quiero ir a verlo con él.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "ir",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "con",
      "él."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "ir",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "con",
      "él."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I have to (must) go and do it today.",
    "answer": "Tengo que ir a hacerlo hoy.",
    "options": [
      "Tengo",
      "que",
      "ir",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Tengo",
      "que",
      "ir",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I have to speak with you.",
    "answer": "Tengo que hablar contigo.",
    "options": [
      "Tengo",
      "que",
      "hablar",
      "contigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Tengo",
      "que",
      "hablar",
      "contigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's going to come and speak with you tomorrow.",
    "answer": "(Ella) va a venir a hablar contigo mañana.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "venir",
      "a",
      "hablar",
      "contigo",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "venir",
      "a",
      "hablar",
      "contigo",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't understand why she doesn’t want to come with you.",
    "answer": "No comprendo por qué (ella) no quiere venir contigo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "comprendo",
      "por",
      "qué",
      "(ella)",
      "no",
      "quiere",
      "venir",
      "contigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "comprendo",
      "por",
      "qué",
      "(ella)",
      "no",
      "quiere",
      "venir",
      "contigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's going to buy the car but it’s very expensive.",
    "answer": "(Ella) va a comprar el carro pero es muy caro.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "comprar",
      "el",
      "carro",
      "pero",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "comprar",
      "el",
      "carro",
      "pero",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "caro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's buying it today.",
    "answer": "Lo compra hoy.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "compra",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "compra",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am buying/I buy",
    "answer": "(yo) compro",
    "options": [
      "(yo)",
      "compro"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(yo)",
      "compro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you are buying/you buy",
    "answer": "(tú) compras",
    "options": [
      "(tú)",
      "compras"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(tú)",
      "compras"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "she is buying/she buys",
    "answer": "(ella) compra",
    "options": [
      "(ella)",
      "compra"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(ella)",
      "compra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you call me?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no me llamas?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "me",
      "llamas?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "me",
      "llamas?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to have dinner",
    "answer": "cenar",
    "options": [
      "cenar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "cenar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time does he have dinner?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora cena?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "cena?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "cena?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to need",
    "answer": "necesitar",
    "options": [
      "necesitar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "necesitar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I need to speak with the teacher.",
    "answer": "Necesito hablar con el profesor.",
    "options": [
      "Necesito",
      "hablar",
      "con",
      "el",
      "profesor."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Necesito",
      "hablar",
      "con",
      "el",
      "profesor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't understand you.",
    "answer": "No te comprendo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "te",
      "comprendo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "te",
      "comprendo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She doesn't understand me.",
    "answer": "(Ella) no me comprende.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "me",
      "comprende."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "me",
      "comprende."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to see",
    "answer": "ver",
    "options": [
      "ver"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "ver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you seeing it tomorrow?",
    "answer": "¿Lo ves mañana?",
    "options": [
      "¿Lo",
      "ves",
      "mañana?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Lo",
      "ves",
      "mañana?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going to see it tomorrow?",
    "answer": "¿Vas a verlo mañana?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "mañana?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "mañana?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to go out/to leave",
    "answer": "salir",
    "options": [
      "salir"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "salir"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going out now.",
    "answer": "Salgo ahora.",
    "options": [
      "Salgo",
      "ahora."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Salgo",
      "ahora."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He's going out soon.",
    "answer": "(Él) sale pronto.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "sale",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "sale",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going out later?",
    "answer": "¿Sales más tarde?",
    "options": [
      "¿Sales",
      "más",
      "tarde?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Sales",
      "más",
      "tarde?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to have",
    "answer": "tener",
    "options": [
      "tener"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "tener"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Don't you have it?",
    "answer": "¿No lo tienes?",
    "options": [
      "¿No",
      "lo",
      "tienes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿No",
      "lo",
      "tienes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why doesn’t he have it?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no lo tiene?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "tiene?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "tiene?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to want",
    "answer": "querer",
    "options": [
      "querer"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "querer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want it.",
    "answer": "Lo quiero.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "quiero."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "quiero."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you want to know why?",
    "answer": "¿Quieres saber por qué?",
    "options": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "saber",
      "por",
      "qué?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "saber",
      "por",
      "qué?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Doesn’t she want to go out?",
    "answer": "¿No quiere salir?",
    "options": [
      "¿No",
      "quiere",
      "salir?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿No",
      "quiere",
      "salir?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to know",
    "answer": "saber",
    "options": [
      "saber"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "saber"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Don't you know?",
    "answer": "¿No sabes?",
    "options": [
      "¿No",
      "sabes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿No",
      "sabes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to do",
    "answer": "hacer",
    "options": [
      "hacer"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "hacer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am doing it now.",
    "answer": "Lo hago ahora.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "hago",
      "ahora."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "hago",
      "ahora."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You do it with her.",
    "answer": "Lo haces con ella.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "haces",
      "con",
      "ella."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "haces",
      "con",
      "ella."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Doesn't she do it with her?",
    "answer": "¿No lo hace con ella?",
    "options": [
      "¿No",
      "lo",
      "hace",
      "con",
      "ella?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿No",
      "lo",
      "hace",
      "con",
      "ella?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to eat/to have lunch",
    "answer": "comer",
    "options": [
      "comer"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "comer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I’m sorry but I'm having lunch.",
    "answer": "Lo siento pero como.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "siento",
      "pero",
      "como."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "siento",
      "pero",
      "como."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are having lunch.",
    "answer": "(Tú) comes.",
    "options": [
      "(Tú)",
      "comes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Tú)",
      "comes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is having lunch with me.",
    "answer": "(Él) come conmigo.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "come",
      "conmigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "come",
      "conmigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I say it.",
    "answer": "Lo digo.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "digo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "digo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You're not saying it.",
    "answer": "No lo dices.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "dices."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "dices."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It doesn’t say it.",
    "answer": "No lo dice.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "dice."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "dice."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I come",
    "answer": "vengo",
    "options": [
      "vengo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "vengo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm coming tomorrow.",
    "answer": "Vengo mañana.",
    "options": [
      "Vengo",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vengo",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you coming with her?",
    "answer": "¿Vienes con ella?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vienes",
      "con",
      "ella?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vienes",
      "con",
      "ella?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is it coming today?",
    "answer": "¿Viene hoy?",
    "options": [
      "¿Viene",
      "hoy?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Viene",
      "hoy?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Is Maria coming with you?",
    "answer": "¿Maria viene contigo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Maria",
      "viene",
      "contigo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Maria",
      "viene",
      "contigo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to sell",
    "answer": "vender",
    "options": [
      "vender"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "vender"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm selling my car.",
    "answer": "Vendo mi carro.",
    "options": [
      "Vendo",
      "mi",
      "carro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vendo",
      "mi",
      "carro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are you selling your house?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué vendes tu casa?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "vendes",
      "tu",
      "casa?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "vendes",
      "tu",
      "casa?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to buy it if she is selling it",
    "answer": "Quiero comprarlo si (ella) lo vende.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprarlo",
      "si",
      "(ella)",
      "lo",
      "vende."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "comprarlo",
      "si",
      "(ella)",
      "lo",
      "vende."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Spain",
    "answer": "España",
    "options": [
      "España"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "España"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like (“it pleases me”)",
    "answer": "me gusta",
    "options": [
      "me",
      "gusta"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "me",
      "gusta"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like Spain. (“Spain pleases me”)",
    "answer": "Me gusta España.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "España."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "España."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like Madrid.",
    "answer": "Me gusta Madrid.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "Madrid."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "Madrid."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like Carlos.",
    "answer": "Me gusta Carlos.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "Carlos."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "Carlos."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like to do it.",
    "answer": "Me gusta hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't like to do it.",
    "answer": "No me gusta hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't like this.",
    "answer": "No me gusta esto.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "esto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "esto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like it.",
    "answer": "Me gusta.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gusta."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gusta."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you like (“it pleases you”)",
    "answer": "te gusta",
    "options": [
      "te",
      "gusta"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "te",
      "gusta"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You like it.",
    "answer": "Te gusta.",
    "options": [
      "Te",
      "gusta."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Te",
      "gusta."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you like it?",
    "answer": "¿Te gusta?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "gusta?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "gusta?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like you. (“you please me”)",
    "answer": "Me gustas.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustas."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustas."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you like Spain?",
    "answer": "¿Te gusta España?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "gusta",
      "España?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "gusta",
      "España?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you like my house?",
    "answer": "¿Te gusta mi casa?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "gusta",
      "mi",
      "casa?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "gusta",
      "mi",
      "casa?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call me!",
    "answer": "¡Llámame!",
    "options": [
      "¡Llámame!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Llámame!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Buy it!",
    "answer": "¡Cómpralo!",
    "options": [
      "¡Cómpralo!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Cómpralo!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Speak!",
    "answer": "¡Habla!",
    "options": [
      "¡Habla!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Habla!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Speak with her!",
    "answer": "¡Habla con ella!",
    "options": [
      "¡Habla",
      "con",
      "ella!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Habla",
      "con",
      "ella!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Speak with him tonight.",
    "answer": "Habla con él esta noche.",
    "options": [
      "Habla",
      "con",
      "él",
      "esta",
      "noche."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Habla",
      "con",
      "él",
      "esta",
      "noche."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Buy two beers.",
    "answer": "Compra dos cervezas.",
    "options": [
      "Compra",
      "dos",
      "cervezas."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Compra",
      "dos",
      "cervezas."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Buy one for me. (a beer)",
    "answer": "Compra una para mí.",
    "options": [
      "Compra",
      "una",
      "para",
      "mí."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Compra",
      "una",
      "para",
      "mí."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call me if it’s not ready",
    "answer": "Llámame si no está listo/a!",
    "options": [
      "Llámame",
      "si",
      "no",
      "está",
      "listo/a!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Llámame",
      "si",
      "no",
      "está",
      "listo/a!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call him!",
    "answer": "¡Llámalo!",
    "options": [
      "¡Llámalo!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Llámalo!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call her!",
    "answer": "¡Llámala!",
    "options": [
      "¡Llámala!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Llámala!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call him if you can’t do it.",
    "answer": "Llámalo si no puedes hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Llámalo",
      "si",
      "no",
      "puedes",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Llámalo",
      "si",
      "no",
      "puedes",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call her if you need a teacher.",
    "answer": "Llámala si necesitas una profesora.",
    "options": [
      "Llámala",
      "si",
      "necesitas",
      "una",
      "profesora."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Llámala",
      "si",
      "necesitas",
      "una",
      "profesora."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call me if you want to speak.",
    "answer": "Llámame si quieres hablar.",
    "options": [
      "Llámame",
      "si",
      "quieres",
      "hablar."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Llámame",
      "si",
      "quieres",
      "hablar."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "put it ...",
    "answer": "ponlo ...",
    "options": [
      "ponlo",
      "..."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "ponlo",
      "..."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Put it here. please.",
    "answer": "Ponlo aquí, por favor.",
    "options": [
      "Ponlo",
      "aquí,",
      "por",
      "favor."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Ponlo",
      "aquí,",
      "por",
      "favor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Put it on the table.",
    "answer": "Ponlo en la mesa.",
    "options": [
      "Ponlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Ponlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm putting it on the chair.",
    "answer": "Lo pongo en la silla.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "pongo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "silla."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "pongo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "silla."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You're putting it on the big table.",
    "answer": "Lo pones en la mesa grande.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "pones",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa",
      "grande."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "pones",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa",
      "grande."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Put it on the small table!",
    "answer": "!Ponlo en la mesa pequeña!",
    "options": [
      "!Ponlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa",
      "pequeña!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "!Ponlo",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa",
      "pequeña!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do it!",
    "answer": "¡Hazlo!",
    "options": [
      "¡Hazlo!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Hazlo!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do it like that.",
    "answer": "Hazlo así.",
    "options": [
      "Hazlo",
      "así."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Hazlo",
      "así."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do it with David.",
    "answer": "Hazlo con David.",
    "options": [
      "Hazlo",
      "con",
      "David."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Hazlo",
      "con",
      "David."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "fast/quickly",
    "answer": "rápido",
    "options": [
      "rápido"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "rápido"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do it quickly!",
    "answer": "¡hazlo rápido!",
    "options": [
      "¡hazlo",
      "rápido!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡hazlo",
      "rápido!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do it very quickly, please!",
    "answer": "¡Hazlo muy rápido, por favor!",
    "options": [
      "¡Hazlo",
      "muy",
      "rápido,",
      "por",
      "favor!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Hazlo",
      "muy",
      "rápido,",
      "por",
      "favor!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "slowly",
    "answer": "despacio",
    "options": [
      "despacio"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "despacio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do it slowly!",
    "answer": "¡Hazlo despacio!",
    "options": [
      "¡Hazlo",
      "despacio!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Hazlo",
      "despacio!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Call her quickly if you want to see her today.",
    "answer": "Llámala rápido si quieres verla hoy.",
    "options": [
      "Llámala",
      "rápido",
      "si",
      "quieres",
      "verla",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Llámala",
      "rápido",
      "si",
      "quieres",
      "verla",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Speak slowly.",
    "answer": "Habla despacio.",
    "options": [
      "Habla",
      "despacio."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Habla",
      "despacio."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "well",
    "answer": "bien",
    "options": [
      "bien"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "bien"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "very well",
    "answer": "muy bien",
    "options": [
      "muy",
      "bien"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "muy",
      "bien"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Speak slowly because he doesn’t understand very well.",
    "answer": "Habla despacio porque (él) no comprende muy bien.",
    "options": [
      "Habla",
      "despacio",
      "porque",
      "(él)",
      "no",
      "comprende",
      "muy",
      "bien."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Habla",
      "despacio",
      "porque",
      "(él)",
      "no",
      "comprende",
      "muy",
      "bien."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She speaks very well.",
    "answer": "(Ella) habla muy bien.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "habla",
      "muy",
      "bien."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "habla",
      "muy",
      "bien."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Very well, thanks.",
    "answer": "Muy bien. Gracias.",
    "options": [
      "Muy",
      "bien.",
      "Gracias."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Muy",
      "bien.",
      "Gracias."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Everything is going well.",
    "answer": "Todo va bien.",
    "options": [
      "Todo",
      "va",
      "bien."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Todo",
      "va",
      "bien."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nothing is going well.",
    "answer": "Nada va bien.",
    "options": [
      "Nada",
      "va",
      "bien."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Nada",
      "va",
      "bien."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Put the chair on the table!",
    "answer": "¡Pon la silla en la mesa!",
    "options": [
      "¡Pon",
      "la",
      "silla",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Pon",
      "la",
      "silla",
      "en",
      "la",
      "mesa!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to put everything here.",
    "answer": "Voy a poner todo aquí.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "poner",
      "todo",
      "aquí."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "poner",
      "todo",
      "aquí."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "on Monday",
    "answer": "el lunes",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "lunes"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "lunes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "on Tuesday",
    "answer": "el martes",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "martes"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "martes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "on Wednesday",
    "answer": "el miércoles",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "miércoles"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "miércoles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "on Thursday",
    "answer": "el jueves",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "jueves"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "jueves"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "on Friday",
    "answer": "el viernes",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "viernes"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "viernes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "on Saturday",
    "answer": "el sábado",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "sábado"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "sábado"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "on Sunday",
    "answer": "el domingo",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "domingo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "domingo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to do it on Monday.",
    "answer": "Voy a hacerlo el lunes.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "el",
      "lunes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "el",
      "lunes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to see her on Tuesday.",
    "answer": "Voy a verla el martes.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "verla",
      "el",
      "martes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "verla",
      "el",
      "martes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to have it on Wednesday.",
    "answer": "Quiero tenerlo el miércoles.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "tenerlo",
      "el",
      "miércoles."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "tenerlo",
      "el",
      "miércoles."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I need it on Thursday.",
    "answer": "Lo necesito el jueves.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "necesito",
      "el",
      "jueves."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "necesito",
      "el",
      "jueves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It has to be ready on Friday.",
    "answer": "Tiene que estar listo el viernes.",
    "options": [
      "Tiene",
      "que",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "el",
      "viernes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Tiene",
      "que",
      "estar",
      "listo",
      "el",
      "viernes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She knows that I am coming on Saturday.",
    "answer": "(Ella) sabe que vengo el sábado.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "sabe",
      "que",
      "vengo",
      "el",
      "sábado."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "sabe",
      "que",
      "vengo",
      "el",
      "sábado."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Today is not Sunday. It’s Monday.",
    "answer": "Hoy no es domingo, es lunes.",
    "options": [
      "Hoy",
      "no",
      "es",
      "domingo,",
      "es",
      "lunes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Hoy",
      "no",
      "es",
      "domingo,",
      "es",
      "lunes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "something",
    "answer": "algo",
    "options": [
      "algo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "algo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I have something for you.",
    "answer": "Tengo algo para ti.",
    "options": [
      "Tengo",
      "algo",
      "para",
      "ti."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Tengo",
      "algo",
      "para",
      "ti."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to buy something for her.",
    "answer": "Voy a comprar algo para ella.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "comprar",
      "algo",
      "para",
      "ella."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "comprar",
      "algo",
      "para",
      "ella."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to tell you something important.",
    "answer": "Ella quiere decirte algo importante.",
    "options": [
      "Ella",
      "quiere",
      "decirte",
      "algo",
      "importante."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Ella",
      "quiere",
      "decirte",
      "algo",
      "importante."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you want to eat something?",
    "answer": "¿Quieres comer algo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "comer",
      "algo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "comer",
      "algo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "a book",
    "answer": "un libro",
    "options": [
      "un",
      "libro"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "un",
      "libro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Buy the book!",
    "answer": "¡Compra el libro!",
    "options": [
      "¡Compra",
      "el",
      "libro!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Compra",
      "el",
      "libro!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "this",
    "answer": "este(masculine)/esta(feminine)",
    "options": [
      "este(masculine)/esta(feminine)"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "este(masculine)/esta(feminine)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "this book",
    "answer": "este libro",
    "options": [
      "este",
      "libro"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "este",
      "libro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "this house",
    "answer": "esta casa",
    "options": [
      "esta",
      "casa"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "esta",
      "casa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "that",
    "answer": "ese/esa",
    "options": [
      "ese/esa"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "ese/esa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "that table",
    "answer": "esa mesa",
    "options": [
      "esa",
      "mesa"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "esa",
      "mesa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "that book",
    "answer": "ese libro",
    "options": [
      "ese",
      "libro"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "ese",
      "libro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "that car",
    "answer": "ese carro",
    "options": [
      "ese",
      "carro"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "ese",
      "carro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like that car.",
    "answer": "Me gusta ese carro.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "ese",
      "carro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "ese",
      "carro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you put this chair on that table?",
    "answer": "¿Puedes poner esta silla en esa mesa?",
    "options": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "poner",
      "esta",
      "silla",
      "en",
      "esa",
      "mesa?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "poner",
      "esta",
      "silla",
      "en",
      "esa",
      "mesa?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "this/that (without noun)",
    "answer": "esto/eso",
    "options": [
      "esto/eso"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "esto/eso"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't want to buy that.",
    "answer": "No quiero comprar eso.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "comprar",
      "eso."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "comprar",
      "eso."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't want to buy that car.",
    "answer": "No quiero comprar ese carro.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "comprar",
      "ese",
      "carro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "comprar",
      "ese",
      "carro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "a man",
    "answer": "un hombre",
    "options": [
      "un",
      "hombre"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "un",
      "hombre"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "a woman",
    "answer": "una mujer",
    "options": [
      "una",
      "mujer"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "una",
      "mujer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like that man.",
    "answer": "Me gusta ese hombre.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "ese",
      "hombre."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gusta",
      "ese",
      "hombre."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't like that woman.",
    "answer": "No me gusta esa mujer.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "esa",
      "mujer."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "esa",
      "mujer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you buy this book?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no compras este libro?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "compras",
      "este",
      "libro?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "compras",
      "este",
      "libro?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Buy that book!",
    "answer": "¡Compra ese libro!",
    "options": [
      "¡Compra",
      "ese",
      "libro!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Compra",
      "ese",
      "libro!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do want to buy that house?",
    "answer": "¿Quieres comprar esa casa?",
    "options": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "comprar",
      "esa",
      "casa?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Quieres",
      "comprar",
      "esa",
      "casa?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He's not buying it. (referring to a feminine item)",
    "answer": "(Él) no la compra.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "no",
      "la",
      "compra."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "no",
      "la",
      "compra."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She's not selling it. (referring to a feminine item)",
    "answer": "(Ella) no la vende.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "la",
      "vende."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "la",
      "vende."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you sell it. (referring to a masculine item)",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no lo vendes?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "vendes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "vendes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "we",
    "answer": "nosotros/nosotras",
    "options": [
      "nosotros/nosotras"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "nosotros/nosotras"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "we speak/we are speaking",
    "answer": "(nosotros/nosotras) hablamos",
    "options": [
      "(nosotros/nosotras)",
      "hablamos"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(nosotros/nosotras)",
      "hablamos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We speak English and Spanish.",
    "answer": "Hablamos inglés y español.",
    "options": [
      "Hablamos",
      "inglés",
      "y",
      "español."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Hablamos",
      "inglés",
      "y",
      "español."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are selling this book.",
    "answer": "(Nosotros/as)vendemos este libro.",
    "options": [
      "(Nosotros/as)vendemos",
      "este",
      "libro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Nosotros/as)vendemos",
      "este",
      "libro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to go out/leave",
    "answer": "salir",
    "options": [
      "salir"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "salir"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When are we going out?",
    "answer": "¿Cuándo salimos?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "salimos?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "salimos?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are not going out today.",
    "answer": "No salimos hoy.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "salimos",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "salimos",
      "hoy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are we doing?",
    "answer": "¿Qué hacemos?",
    "options": [
      "¿Qué",
      "hacemos?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Qué",
      "hacemos?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When are we seeing the house?",
    "answer": "¿Cuándo vemos la casa?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "vemos",
      "la",
      "casa?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "vemos",
      "la",
      "casa?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We know where you are.",
    "answer": "Sabemos dónde estás.",
    "options": [
      "Sabemos",
      "dónde",
      "estás."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Sabemos",
      "dónde",
      "estás."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are coming on Friday.",
    "answer": "Venimos el viernes.",
    "options": [
      "Venimos",
      "el",
      "viernes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Venimos",
      "el",
      "viernes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are putting it here.",
    "answer": "Lo ponemos aquí.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "ponemos",
      "aquí."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "ponemos",
      "aquí."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to understand",
    "answer": "comprender",
    "options": [
      "comprender"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "comprender"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We don’t understand why you have to say it.",
    "answer": "No comprendemos por qué tienes que decirlo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "comprendemos",
      "por",
      "qué",
      "tienes",
      "que",
      "decirlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "comprendemos",
      "por",
      "qué",
      "tienes",
      "que",
      "decirlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to go",
    "answer": "ir",
    "options": [
      "ir"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "ir"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to go.",
    "answer": "Quiero ir.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "ir."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "ir."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She wants to go with you.",
    "answer": "(Ella) quiere ir contigo.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "ir",
      "contigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "quiere",
      "ir",
      "contigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going",
    "answer": "voy",
    "options": [
      "voy"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "voy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to(a destination)",
    "answer": "a",
    "options": [
      "a"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "a"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm going to Barcelona.",
    "answer": "Voy a Barcelona.",
    "options": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "Barcelona."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Voy",
      "a",
      "Barcelona."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "are you going?",
    "answer": "¿vas?",
    "options": [
      "¿vas?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿vas?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going with her?",
    "answer": "¿Vas con ella?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vas",
      "con",
      "ella?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vas",
      "con",
      "ella?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He's not going because it’s very late.",
    "answer": "(Él) no va porque es muy tarde.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "no",
      "va",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "no",
      "va",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "we are going/we go",
    "answer": "(nosotros/as)vamos",
    "options": [
      "(nosotros/as)vamos"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(nosotros/as)vamos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are going to Madrid.",
    "answer": "Vamos a Madrid.",
    "options": [
      "Vamos",
      "a",
      "Madrid."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vamos",
      "a",
      "Madrid."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are going to do it.",
    "answer": "Vamos a hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Vamos",
      "a",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vamos",
      "a",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "too",
    "answer": "demasiado",
    "options": [
      "demasiado"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "demasiado"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are not going to do it because it’s too difficult.",
    "answer": "No vamos a hacerlo porque es demasiado difícil.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "vamos",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "difícil."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "vamos",
      "a",
      "hacerlo",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "difícil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I’m sorry but I don’t understand you because you speak too fast.",
    "answer": "Lo siento pero no te comprendo porque hablas demasiado rápido.",
    "options": [
      "Lo",
      "siento",
      "pero",
      "no",
      "te",
      "comprendo",
      "porque",
      "hablas",
      "demasiado",
      "rápido."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Lo",
      "siento",
      "pero",
      "no",
      "te",
      "comprendo",
      "porque",
      "hablas",
      "demasiado",
      "rápido."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you don’t understand, we are going to speak slowly.",
    "answer": "Si no comprendes, vamos a hablar despacio.",
    "options": [
      "Si",
      "no",
      "comprendes,",
      "vamos",
      "a",
      "hablar",
      "despacio."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Si",
      "no",
      "comprendes,",
      "vamos",
      "a",
      "hablar",
      "despacio."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's too soon for her.",
    "answer": "Es demasiado pronto para ella.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "demasiado",
      "pronto",
      "para",
      "ella."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "demasiado",
      "pronto",
      "para",
      "ella."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's too late for him.",
    "answer": "Es demasiado tarde para él.",
    "options": [
      "Es",
      "demasiado",
      "tarde",
      "para",
      "él."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Es",
      "demasiado",
      "tarde",
      "para",
      "él."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can't do it because it's too small.",
    "answer": "No puedo hacerlo porque es demasiado pequeño.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "hacerlo",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "pequeño."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "hacerlo",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "pequeño."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If it’s too late now, we can go tomorrow.",
    "answer": "Si es demasiado tarde ahora, podemos ir mañana.",
    "options": [
      "Si",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "tarde",
      "ahora,",
      "podemos",
      "ir",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Si",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "tarde",
      "ahora,",
      "podemos",
      "ir",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Good morning",
    "answer": "Buenos días",
    "options": [
      "Buenos",
      "días"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Buenos",
      "días"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Good afternoon/evening",
    "answer": "Buenas tardes",
    "options": [
      "Buenas",
      "tardes"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Buenas",
      "tardes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Good night",
    "answer": "Buenas noches",
    "options": [
      "Buenas",
      "noches"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Buenas",
      "noches"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "a room",
    "answer": "una habitación",
    "options": [
      "una",
      "habitación"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "una",
      "habitación"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "a television",
    "answer": "una televisión",
    "options": [
      "una",
      "televisión"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "una",
      "televisión"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Good afternoon. Do you have a room for two?",
    "answer": "Buenas tardes. ¿Tienes una habitación para dos?",
    "options": [
      "Buenas",
      "tardes.",
      "¿Tienes",
      "una",
      "habitación",
      "para",
      "dos?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Buenas",
      "tardes.",
      "¿Tienes",
      "una",
      "habitación",
      "para",
      "dos?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Good afternoon. I want a room with a television.",
    "answer": "Buenas tardes. Quiero una habitación con una televisión.",
    "options": [
      "Buenas",
      "tardes.",
      "Quiero",
      "una",
      "habitación",
      "con",
      "una",
      "televisión."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Buenas",
      "tardes.",
      "Quiero",
      "una",
      "habitación",
      "con",
      "una",
      "televisión."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Good morning. Are you the teacher?",
    "answer": "Buenos días. ¿Eres el profesor?",
    "options": [
      "Buenos",
      "días.",
      "¿Eres",
      "el",
      "profesor?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Buenos",
      "días.",
      "¿Eres",
      "el",
      "profesor?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to live",
    "answer": "vivir",
    "options": [
      "vivir"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "vivir"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you live here?",
    "answer": "¿Vives aquí?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vives",
      "aquí?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vives",
      "aquí?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I live with him and with her.",
    "answer": "Vivo con él y con ella.",
    "options": [
      "Vivo",
      "con",
      "él",
      "y",
      "con",
      "ella."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vivo",
      "con",
      "él",
      "y",
      "con",
      "ella."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She doesn't live in this house.",
    "answer": "Ella no vive en esta casa.",
    "options": [
      "Ella",
      "no",
      "vive",
      "en",
      "esta",
      "casa."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Ella",
      "no",
      "vive",
      "en",
      "esta",
      "casa."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "one, two, thee, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten",
    "answer": "uno, dos, tres, cuatro, cinco, seis, siete, ocho, nueve, diez",
    "options": [
      "uno,",
      "dos,",
      "tres,",
      "cuatro,",
      "cinco,",
      "seis,",
      "siete,",
      "ocho,",
      "nueve,",
      "diez"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "uno,",
      "dos,",
      "tres,",
      "cuatro,",
      "cinco,",
      "seis,",
      "siete,",
      "ocho,",
      "nueve,",
      "diez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "number six",
    "answer": "el número seis",
    "options": [
      "el",
      "número",
      "seis"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "el",
      "número",
      "seis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Number six is easy.",
    "answer": "El número seis es fácil.",
    "options": [
      "El",
      "número",
      "seis",
      "es",
      "fácil."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "El",
      "número",
      "seis",
      "es",
      "fácil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Number three is difficult.",
    "answer": "El número tres es difícil.",
    "options": [
      "El",
      "número",
      "tres",
      "es",
      "difícil."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "El",
      "número",
      "tres",
      "es",
      "difícil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to do number nine.",
    "answer": "Quiero hacer el número nueve.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "hacer",
      "el",
      "número",
      "nueve."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "hacer",
      "el",
      "número",
      "nueve."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Number one is too easy.",
    "answer": "El número uno es demasiado fácil.",
    "options": [
      "El",
      "número",
      "uno",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "fácil."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "El",
      "número",
      "uno",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "fácil."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do number 10!",
    "answer": "¡Haz el número diez!",
    "options": [
      "¡Haz",
      "el",
      "número",
      "diez!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Haz",
      "el",
      "número",
      "diez!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We’re going to do number five later.",
    "answer": "Vamos a hacer el número cinco más tarde.",
    "options": [
      "Vamos",
      "a",
      "hacer",
      "el",
      "número",
      "cinco",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vamos",
      "a",
      "hacer",
      "el",
      "número",
      "cinco",
      "más",
      "tarde."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't like number eight.",
    "answer": "No me gusta el número ocho.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "el",
      "número",
      "ocho."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "el",
      "número",
      "ocho."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She lives in number two.",
    "answer": "(Ella) vive en el número dos.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "vive",
      "en",
      "el",
      "número",
      "dos."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "vive",
      "en",
      "el",
      "número",
      "dos."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I live in a small house but my room is very big.",
    "answer": "Vivo en una casa pequeña pero mi habitación es muy grande.",
    "options": [
      "Vivo",
      "en",
      "una",
      "casa",
      "pequeña",
      "pero",
      "mi",
      "habitación",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "grande."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vivo",
      "en",
      "una",
      "casa",
      "pequeña",
      "pero",
      "mi",
      "habitación",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "grande."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to give",
    "answer": "dar",
    "options": [
      "dar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "dar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Can you give me the book, please?",
    "answer": "¿Puedes darme el libro, por favor?",
    "options": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "darme",
      "el",
      "libro,",
      "por",
      "favor?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Puedes",
      "darme",
      "el",
      "libro,",
      "por",
      "favor?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Give me five euros!",
    "answer": "¡Dame cinco euros!",
    "options": [
      "¡Dame",
      "cinco",
      "euros!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Dame",
      "cinco",
      "euros!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are giving me the book.",
    "answer": "Me das el libro.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "das",
      "el",
      "libro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "das",
      "el",
      "libro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I’m giving you the book",
    "answer": "Te doy el libro.",
    "options": [
      "Te",
      "doy",
      "el",
      "libro."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Te",
      "doy",
      "el",
      "libro."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She calls me.",
    "answer": "Me llama.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "llama."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "llama."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She calls me on Wednesday.",
    "answer": "(Ella) me llama el miércoles.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "me",
      "llama",
      "el",
      "miércoles."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "me",
      "llama",
      "el",
      "miércoles."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She doesn't call you.",
    "answer": "(Ella) no te llama.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "te",
      "llama."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "te",
      "llama."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She doesn’t call you on Friday.",
    "answer": "(Ella) no te llama el viernes.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "te",
      "llama",
      "el",
      "viernes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "no",
      "te",
      "llama",
      "el",
      "viernes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You don't understand me.",
    "answer": "No me comprendes.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "comprendes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "comprendes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He understands me very well.",
    "answer": "(Él) me comprende muy bien.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "me",
      "comprende",
      "muy",
      "bien."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "me",
      "comprende",
      "muy",
      "bien."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She tells me everything.",
    "answer": "(Ella) me dice todo.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "me",
      "dice",
      "todo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "me",
      "dice",
      "todo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you understand me?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no me comprendes?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "me",
      "comprendes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "me",
      "comprendes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why doesn't she call me?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué (ella) no me llama?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "(ella)",
      "no",
      "me",
      "llama?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "(ella)",
      "no",
      "me",
      "llama?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you want/love me?",
    "answer": "¿Me quieres?",
    "options": [
      "¿Me",
      "quieres?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Me",
      "quieres?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I love you.",
    "answer": "Te quiero.",
    "options": [
      "Te",
      "quiero."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Te",
      "quiero."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She loves me.",
    "answer": "(Ella) me quiere.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "me",
      "quiere."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "me",
      "quiere."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I want to tell you something.",
    "answer": "Quiero decirte algo.",
    "options": [
      "Quiero",
      "decirte",
      "algo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Quiero",
      "decirte",
      "algo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you (informal)",
    "answer": "tú",
    "options": [
      "tú"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "tú"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you(formal)",
    "answer": "usted",
    "options": [
      "usted"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "usted"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How are you? (informal)",
    "answer": "¿Cómo estás?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "estás?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "estás?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is he/she?",
    "answer": "¿Cómo está (él/ella)?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(él/ella)?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(él/ella)?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How are you?(formal)",
    "answer": "¿Cómo está (usted)?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(usted)?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cómo",
      "está",
      "(usted)?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you have (formal)",
    "answer": "(usted) tiene",
    "options": [
      "(usted)",
      "tiene"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(usted)",
      "tiene"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you have? (formal)",
    "answer": "¿Qué tiene (usted)?",
    "options": [
      "¿Qué",
      "tiene",
      "(usted)?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Qué",
      "tiene",
      "(usted)?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you speak English? (formal)",
    "answer": "¿Habla (usted) inglés?",
    "options": [
      "¿Habla",
      "(usted)",
      "inglés?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Habla",
      "(usted)",
      "inglés?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you want to buy my car? (formal)",
    "answer": "¿Quiere (usted) comprar mi carro?",
    "options": [
      "¿Quiere",
      "(usted)",
      "comprar",
      "mi",
      "carro?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Quiere",
      "(usted)",
      "comprar",
      "mi",
      "carro?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to start",
    "answer": "empezar",
    "options": [
      "empezar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "empezar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I start",
    "answer": "(yo) empiezo",
    "options": [
      "(yo)",
      "empiezo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(yo)",
      "empiezo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "you start",
    "answer": "(tú) empiezas",
    "options": [
      "(tú)",
      "empiezas"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(tú)",
      "empiezas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "he/she/it/you (formal) starts",
    "answer": "(él, ella, usted) empieza  (no pronoun for “it” in Spanish)",
    "options": [
      "(él,",
      "ella,",
      "usted)",
      "empieza"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(él,",
      "ella,",
      "usted)",
      "empieza"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "we start",
    "answer": "(nosotros/as) empezamos",
    "options": [
      "(nosotros/as)",
      "empezamos"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(nosotros/as)",
      "empezamos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am starting/I start",
    "answer": "empiezo",
    "options": [
      "empiezo"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "empiezo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time are you starting? (informal)",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora empiezas?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "empiezas?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "empiezas?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time do we start tonight?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora empezamos esta noche?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "empezamos",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "empezamos",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When is it starting?/When does it start?",
    "answer": "¿Cuándo empieza?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "empieza?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "empieza?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When do you start? (formal)",
    "answer": "¿Cuándo empieza (usted)?",
    "options": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "empieza",
      "(usted)?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Cuándo",
      "empieza",
      "(usted)?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to think",
    "answer": "pensar",
    "options": [
      "pensar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "pensar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "of",
    "answer": "de",
    "options": [
      "de"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "de"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you (informal) think of my telephone?",
    "answer": "¿Qué piensas de mi teléfono?",
    "options": [
      "¿Qué",
      "piensas",
      "de",
      "mi",
      "teléfono?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Qué",
      "piensas",
      "de",
      "mi",
      "teléfono?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you think of my new computer?",
    "answer": "¿Qué piensas de mi computadora nuevo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Qué",
      "piensas",
      "de",
      "mi",
      "computadora",
      "nuevo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Qué",
      "piensas",
      "de",
      "mi",
      "computadora",
      "nuevo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I think that I need a new car.",
    "answer": "Pienso que necesito un carro nuevo.",
    "options": [
      "Pienso",
      "que",
      "necesito",
      "un",
      "carro",
      "nuevo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Pienso",
      "que",
      "necesito",
      "un",
      "carro",
      "nuevo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We think it’s very important to start soon.",
    "answer": "(Nosotros/as) pensamos que es muy importante empezar pronto.",
    "options": [
      "(Nosotros/as)",
      "pensamos",
      "que",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "importante",
      "empezar",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Nosotros/as)",
      "pensamos",
      "que",
      "es",
      "muy",
      "importante",
      "empezar",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't understand it.",
    "answer": "(Yo) no lo entiendo.",
    "options": [
      "(Yo)",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "entiendo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Yo)",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "entiendo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don't you (informal) understand me?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no me entiendes?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "me",
      "entiendes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "me",
      "entiendes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I understand why you (informal) want to live there.",
    "answer": "Entiendo por qué quieres vivir allí.",
    "options": [
      "Entiendo",
      "por",
      "qué",
      "quieres",
      "vivir",
      "allí."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Entiendo",
      "por",
      "qué",
      "quieres",
      "vivir",
      "allí."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't understand her.",
    "answer": "No la entiendo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "la",
      "entiendo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "la",
      "entiendo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't understand him.",
    "answer": "No lo entiendo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "entiendo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "entiendo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't understand it..",
    "answer": "No lo entiendo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "entiendo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "lo",
      "entiendo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can't understand him.",
    "answer": "No puedo entenderlo.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "entenderlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "puedo",
      "entenderlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't know if you (informal) understand him",
    "answer": "No sé si lo entiendes.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "lo",
      "entiendes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "sé",
      "si",
      "lo",
      "entiendes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Do you (informal) understand me?",
    "answer": "¿Me entiendes?",
    "options": [
      "¿Me",
      "entiendes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Me",
      "entiendes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't know if you see her.",
    "answer": "No se si la ves.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "se",
      "si",
      "la",
      "ves."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "se",
      "si",
      "la",
      "ves."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you going to see her today?",
    "answer": "¿Vas a verla hoy?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "verla",
      "hoy?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vas",
      "a",
      "verla",
      "hoy?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She is going to see him tomorrow.",
    "answer": "(Ella) va a verlo mañana.",
    "options": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Ella)",
      "va",
      "a",
      "verlo",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "what kind of...?",
    "answer": "¿qué tipo de...?",
    "options": [
      "¿qué",
      "tipo",
      "de...?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿qué",
      "tipo",
      "de...?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of room do you (informal) want?",
    "answer": "¿Qué tipo de habitación quieres?",
    "options": [
      "¿Qué",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "habitación",
      "quieres?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Qué",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "habitación",
      "quieres?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of car do you have?",
    "answer": "¿Qué tipo de carro  tienes?",
    "options": [
      "¿Qué",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "carro",
      "",
      "tienes?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Qué",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "carro",
      "",
      "tienes?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't like this kind of beer.",
    "answer": "No me gusta este tipo de cerveza.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "este",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "cerveza."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gusta",
      "este",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "cerveza."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don’t want that that kind of man.",
    "answer": "No quiero ese tipo de hombre.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "ese",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "hombre."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "ese",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "hombre."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I like",
    "answer": "me gusta",
    "options": [
      "me",
      "gusta"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "me",
      "gusta"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to do it.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría hacerlo.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "hacerlo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "hacerlo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to see it with you.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría verlo contigo.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "verlo",
      "contigo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "verlo",
      "contigo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to start now if it’s possible.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría empezar ahora si es posible.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "empezar",
      "ahora",
      "si",
      "es",
      "posible."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "empezar",
      "ahora",
      "si",
      "es",
      "posible."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to eat something new and different.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría comer algo nuevo y diferente.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "comer",
      "algo",
      "nuevo",
      "y",
      "diferente."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "comer",
      "algo",
      "nuevo",
      "y",
      "diferente."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to give you something.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría darte algo.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "darte",
      "algo."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "darte",
      "algo."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I wouldn’t like",
    "answer": "No me gustaría",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I wouldn't like to live in Madrid.",
    "answer": "No me gustaría vivir en Madrid.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría",
      "vivir",
      "en",
      "Madrid."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría",
      "vivir",
      "en",
      "Madrid."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I wouldn't like to have that room because it’s too small.",
    "answer": "No me gustaría tener esa habitación porque es demasiado pequeña.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría",
      "tener",
      "esa",
      "habitación",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "pequeña."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría",
      "tener",
      "esa",
      "habitación",
      "porque",
      "es",
      "demasiado",
      "pequeña."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to go to Málaga tomorrow.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría ir a Málaga mañana.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "ir",
      "a",
      "Málaga",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "ir",
      "a",
      "Málaga",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I wouldn't like to be a woman.",
    "answer": "No me gustaría ser una mujer.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría",
      "ser",
      "una",
      "mujer."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "me",
      "gustaría",
      "ser",
      "una",
      "mujer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to see it on Tuesday.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría verlo el martes.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "verlo",
      "el",
      "martes."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "verlo",
      "el",
      "martes."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I would like to see him soon.",
    "answer": "Me gustaría verlo pronto.",
    "options": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "verlo",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Me",
      "gustaría",
      "verlo",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Would you like to...?",
    "answer": "¿Te gustaría...?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría...?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría...?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Would you like to have dinner with me?",
    "answer": "¿Te gustaría cenar conmigo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría",
      "cenar",
      "conmigo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría",
      "cenar",
      "conmigo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Would you like to see her later?",
    "answer": "¿Te gustaría verla más tarde?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría",
      "verla",
      "más",
      "tarde?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría",
      "verla",
      "más",
      "tarde?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Would you like to tell me something?",
    "answer": "¿Te gustaría decirme algo?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría",
      "decirme",
      "algo?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "gustaría",
      "decirme",
      "algo?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to be able",
    "answer": "poder",
    "options": [
      "poder"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "poder"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I can, you can, he/she/it can, we can",
    "answer": "puedo, puedes, puede, podemos",
    "options": [
      "puedo,",
      "puedes,",
      "puede,",
      "podemos"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "puedo,",
      "puedes,",
      "puede,",
      "podemos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We can buy a new house if you want.",
    "answer": "(Nosotros/as) podemos comprar una casa nueva si quieres.",
    "options": [
      "(Nosotros/as)",
      "podemos",
      "comprar",
      "una",
      "casa",
      "nueva",
      "si",
      "quieres."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Nosotros/as)",
      "podemos",
      "comprar",
      "una",
      "casa",
      "nueva",
      "si",
      "quieres."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I think she can see it tomorrow.",
    "answer": "Pienso que (ella) puede verlo mañana.",
    "options": [
      "Pienso",
      "que",
      "(ella)",
      "puede",
      "verlo",
      "mañana."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Pienso",
      "que",
      "(ella)",
      "puede",
      "verlo",
      "mañana."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't want to start today if she can’t be here.",
    "answer": "No quiero empezar hoy si (ella) no puede estar aquí.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "empezar",
      "hoy",
      "si",
      "(ella)",
      "no",
      "puede",
      "estar",
      "aquí."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "quiero",
      "empezar",
      "hoy",
      "si",
      "(ella)",
      "no",
      "puede",
      "estar",
      "aquí."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You can't do it in this type of room.",
    "answer": "No puedes hacerlo en este tipo de habitación.",
    "options": [
      "No",
      "puedes",
      "hacerlo",
      "en",
      "este",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "habitación."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "No",
      "puedes",
      "hacerlo",
      "en",
      "este",
      "tipo",
      "de",
      "habitación."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It's going to be difficult to do it if he can’t give you the computer.",
    "answer": "Va a ser difícil hacerlo si (él) no puede darte la computadora",
    "options": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "ser",
      "difícil",
      "hacerlo",
      "si",
      "(él)",
      "no",
      "puede",
      "darte",
      "la",
      "computadora"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Va",
      "a",
      "ser",
      "difícil",
      "hacerlo",
      "si",
      "(él)",
      "no",
      "puede",
      "darte",
      "la",
      "computadora"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to come back",
    "answer": "volver",
    "options": [
      "volver"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "volver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I'm coming back soon.",
    "answer": "Vuelvo pronto.",
    "options": [
      "Vuelvo",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "Vuelvo",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time are you coming back?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora vuelves?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vuelves?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "vuelves?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you coming back tonight?",
    "answer": "¿Vuelves esta noche?",
    "options": [
      "¿Vuelves",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Vuelves",
      "esta",
      "noche?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We are coming back with Maria.",
    "answer": "(Nosotros/as) volvemos con Maria.",
    "options": [
      "(Nosotros/as)",
      "volvemos",
      "con",
      "Maria."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Nosotros/as)",
      "volvemos",
      "con",
      "Maria."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "to raise up/lift",
    "answer": "levantar",
    "options": [
      "levantar"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "levantar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am lifting it up.",
    "answer": "(Yo) lo levanto.",
    "options": [
      "(Yo)",
      "lo",
      "levanto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Yo)",
      "lo",
      "levanto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why don’t you lift it up?",
    "answer": "¿Por qué no lo levantas?",
    "options": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "levantas?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Por",
      "qué",
      "no",
      "lo",
      "levantas?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lift her up!",
    "answer": "¡Levántala!",
    "options": [
      "¡Levántala!"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¡Levántala!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am lifting her up.",
    "answer": "(Yo) la levanto.",
    "options": [
      "(Yo)",
      "la",
      "levanto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Yo)",
      "la",
      "levanto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I am getting up/lifting myself up.",
    "answer": "(Yo) me levanto.",
    "options": [
      "(Yo)",
      "me",
      "levanto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Yo)",
      "me",
      "levanto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are getting up.",
    "answer": "(Tú) te levantas.",
    "options": [
      "(Tú)",
      "te",
      "levantas."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Tú)",
      "te",
      "levantas."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you getting up now?",
    "answer": "¿Te levantas ahora?",
    "options": [
      "¿Te",
      "levantas",
      "ahora?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿Te",
      "levantas",
      "ahora?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "¿At what time do you get up?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora te levantas?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "te",
      "levantas?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "te",
      "levantas?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She/he/it gets up(himself/herself)",
    "answer": "se levanta",
    "options": [
      "se",
      "levanta"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "se",
      "levanta"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time does she get up?",
    "answer": "¿A qué hora se levanta?",
    "options": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "se",
      "levanta?"
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "¿A",
      "qué",
      "hora",
      "se",
      "levanta?"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He's getting up soon.",
    "answer": "(Él) se levanta pronto.",
    "options": [
      "(Él)",
      "se",
      "levanta",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Él)",
      "se",
      "levanta",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I’m going to get up soon.",
    "answer": "(Yo) voy a levantarme pronto.",
    "options": [
      "(Yo)",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "levantarme",
      "pronto."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Yo)",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "levantarme",
      "pronto."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I have to get up soon because I’m going to be very busy today.",
    "answer": "(Yo) tengo que levantarme pronto porque voy a estar muy ocupado/a hoy.",
    "options": [
      "(Yo)",
      "tengo",
      "que",
      "levantarme",
      "pronto",
      "porque",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "muy",
      "ocupado/a",
      "hoy."
    ],
    "answerarray": [
      "(Yo)",
      "tengo",
      "que",
      "levantarme",
      "pronto",
      "porque",
      "voy",
      "a",
      "estar",
      "muy",
      "ocupado/a",
      "hoy."
    ]
  }
]